NICOLE GRANVILLE

S O F T W A R E E N G I N E E R

CONTACT ME

- Portland, OR
- <u>(971) 230 88</u>62
- github.com/ngran4
- in @nicolelgranville

EDUCATION

Oregon State University

2014-2017

Bachelor of Science in Biology Minor in Chemistry

General Assembly

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022
Certificate of Completion
Software Engineering Immersive

SKILLS SUMMARY

- HTML/CSS
- lavascrint
- Node is
- Python
- Django
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- JSON

SUMMARY

Ex-Medical Student transitioning into a Software Development role after completing General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive. Hands-on project experience building both front-end and back-end web apps using object-oriented programming and RESTful APIs. I am a dedicated problem-solver and life-long learner with an eagerness to grow in the field of software engineering.

PROJECTS

Paddle NW

GitHub link: https://github.com/ngran4/Paddle-NW-App

- Full-stack MERN application incorporating Mapbox API and Amazon AWS.
- Designed and implemented an application to find areas for kayaking and paddleboarding.
- Allows users to view a location by map or list view, and upload photos from their adventure.

Plant Parenthood

Github link: https://github.com/ngran4/Plant-Parenthood

- Technologies used: Python, Django, Postgre SQL, Amazon AWS.
- Designed and implemented a plant care application using SCRUM methodology in a 4-person team over the course of 1 week.
- Allows users to add their houseplants by latin and common name, set up watering and fertilizing schedules, and upload photos to track progress.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Marketing Assistant

FETCH Eyewear | March 2021 - January 2022

- Assisted with the development and implementation of campaigns to build brand identity and increase brand awareness.
- Assisted in the management of social media, including content creation and customer relations.

Emergency Department Medical Scribe

Kaiser Permanente | June 2018 - March 2021

- Performed medical documentation of over 3000 patients; including recording medical data, care plans, and diagnosis.
- Organized treatment protocols in a fast-paced emergency room environment.
- Monitored patient medical charts and recognized data discrepancies which were then reported to the attending physician.